{
  "title": "Roald Dahl Quiz!",
  "listOfQuestions": [
    {
      "question": "What is Roald Dahl's most famous children's book?",
      "correctAnswer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Matilda", "The BFG", "James and the Giant Peach"],
      "timeout": 15
    },
    {
      "question": "In which country was Roald Dahl born?",
      "correctAnswer": "Wales",
      "wrongAnswers": ["England", "Norway", "Scotland"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What was Roald Dahl's profession before becoming a writer?",
      "correctAnswer": "Pilot",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Doctor", "Teacher", "Soldier"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which character is a giant friendly giant?",
      "correctAnswer": "The BFG",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Willy Wonka", "Matilda", "James"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of animal is Fantastic Mr. Fox?",
      "correctAnswer": "Fox",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Rabbit", "Owl", "Badger"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which book features a child who can move objects with her mind?",
      "correctAnswer": "Matilda",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The Witches", "The BFG", "Danny the Champion of the World"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who or what is the main antagonist in 'The Witches'?",
      "correctAnswer": "The Grand High Witch",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The Boy", "The Chef", "The Cat"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Roald Dahl served in which war?",
      "correctAnswer": "World War II",
      "wrongAnswers": ["World War I", "Vietnam War", "Korean War"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What did Roald Dahl call his writing shed?",
      "correctAnswer": "The Gabbleduck",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The Writing Hut", "The Imagination Station", "The Dream Room"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In which book do children find a magical peach?",
      "correctAnswer": "James and the Giant Peach",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "The Twits", "The Giraffe and the Pelly and Me"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these stories is NOT written by Roald Dahl?",
      "correctAnswer": "The Tale of Peter Rabbit",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The Enormous Crocodile", "The BFG", "Matilda"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the names of the two main characters in 'Danny the Champion of the World'?",
      "correctAnswer": "Danny and his father",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Charlie and Willy", "Matilda and Miss Trunchbull", "James and the Giant"],
      "timeout": 15
    },
    {
      "question": "What profession did Roald Dahl have during his time in the war?",
      "correctAnswer": "A fighter pilot",
      "wrongAnswers": ["A medic", "An engineer", "A logistics officer"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In 'Charlie and the Chocolate Factory', what is the name of the chocolate factory owner?",
      "correctAnswer": "Willy Wonka",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Charlie Bucket", "Veruca Salt", "Augustus Gloop"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Roald Dahl book features magical children attending a special school?",
      "correctAnswer": "Matilda",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The Witches", "The Twits", "The Giraffe and the Pelly and Me"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Roald Dahl's stories often have what kind of ending?",
      "correctAnswer": "A twist",
      "wrongAnswers": ["A happy conclusion", "An open ending", "A sad conclusion"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What inspired Roald Dahl to write children's books?",
      "correctAnswer": "His love for storytelling",
      "wrongAnswers": ["His childhood experiences", "His children", "His travels"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of Roald Dahl's stories was adapted into an animated movie by Pixar?",
      "correctAnswer": "The BFG",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Matilda", "James and the Giant Peach", "The Magic Finger"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the recurring theme in many of Dahl's children's books?",
      "correctAnswer": "Good vs. Evil",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Love and Friendship", "Adventure and Discovery", "Family Values"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Roald Dahl created a character known for his love of sweets and chocolate. What is the name of this character?",
      "correctAnswer": "Willy Wonka",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Mr. Fox", "Mr. Twit", "Mr. Wormwood"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Roald Dahlâ€™s full birth name?",
      "correctAnswer": "Roald Dahl",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Roald Dhalson", "Roald Dhal", "Roald Dahlen"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which book features a girl who loves to read and has magical powers?",
      "correctAnswer": "Matilda",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "The Witches", "The BFG"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In 'The Twits', what are Mr. and Mrs. Twit known for?",
      "correctAnswer": "Their nasty tricks",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Their kindness", "Their cleanliness", "Their love for pets"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of creature is the BFG?",
      "correctAnswer": "A giant",
      "wrongAnswers": ["A troll", "A fairy", "A wizard"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Roald Dahl wrote poetry in addition to children's books. What was the title of his famous collection?",
      "correctAnswer": "Revolting Rhymes",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Twisted Tales", "Dahl's Rhyme Time", "Funny Verses"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In 'The Witches', what do witches hate the most?",
      "correctAnswer": "Children",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Animals", "Ice cream", "Rats"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relationship between Charlie and Grandpa Joe in 'Charlie and the Chocolate Factory'?",
      "correctAnswer": "Grandson and grandfather",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Cousins", "Brother and sister", "Father and son"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which book tells the story of a magical giraffe, a pelican, and a monkey traveling to save a man?",
      "correctAnswer": "The Giraffe and the Pelly and Me",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Matilda", "James and the Giant Peach", "The Twits"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of food does the giant in 'The BFG' eat?",
      "correctAnswer": "Green and crumbly",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Sweets and cakes", "Fruits and vegetables", "Meat and bread"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What character in Roald Dahl's books often displays cleverness and bravery?",
      "correctAnswer": "The child protagonists",
      "wrongAnswers": ["The adults", "The villains", "The animals"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In which book do children compete for a golden ticket?",
      "correctAnswer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Matilda", "The Twits", "The Witches"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the magical fruit in 'James and the Giant Peach'?",
      "correctAnswer": "A giant peach",
      "wrongAnswers": ["A magical apple", "A talking banana", "A golden pear"],
      "timeout": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Where did Roald Dahl spend much of his childhood?",
      "correctAnswer": "Norway",
      "wrongAnswers": ["Sweden", "Denmark", "Finland"],
      "timeout": 10
    }
  ],
  "time given": ""
}

